

Bryan Ramirez

Full-Stack Developer



Professional Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 2 years of related experience.



Work History

2023-10 -Current

Front-End Developer

Media Revolution, Distrito Nacional, DR

- Contributed to projects within Scrum project management environments.
- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals.
- Advocated for well-tested and documented, high quality code.
- Working on developing complete web applications on both backend and frontend
- Worked closely with back-end developers to integrate RESTful APIs for dynamic data handling within applications.
- Developed reusable components and libraries for future use, accelerating development processes and maintaining consistency across projects.
- Contributed to documentation efforts by creating comprehensive guides on front-end features and system architecture design decisions.
- Participated in agile development processes through regular stand-ups, sprint planning sessions, reviews, and retrospectives.
- Streamlined codebase by refactoring legacy



Address

Santo Domingo, DR,11501

Phone

+1 (829)-647-0438

E-mail

bryantro855@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/i n/bryan-ramirez-ogando/



- Git
- Typescript
- TailwindCSS
- NodeJS
- SASS
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- React
- GitHub
- React.js
- Firebase
- MySQL
- SQL
- MongoDB



Performance Optimization
API Integration
React.js Proficiency
Express.js Familiarity
Typescript Proficiency

- code, resulting in improved maintainability and reduced technical debt.
- Utilized various front-end frameworks
 React,NextJS,Vite for efficient application
 development and seamless integration of UI components.

2022-04 - Full-Stack Developer

Independent, Santo Domingo, DR

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Advised internal users on web service capabilities, principles and protocols.
- I develop and interpret personal projects using the latest front end development technologies today

(Si)

Education

2023-01 -Current

2023-08

Current

Systems Engineering And Computing

O&M College - Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

2023-02 - Frontend Development With React

Coderhouse - Remote

2023-02 - Web Development

2023-04 Coderhouse - Remote

2023-04 - **JavaScript**

2023-06 Coderhouse – Remote

2023-10 -2023-11

TypeScript

Udemy - Remote